为了使它变得有形，我们将考虑我的手机的例子。
To make it tangible, we are going to consider the example of my mobile phone.
我要做的第一件事是将一个右手坐标框架附加到它上面
First thing I am going to do is to attach a right handed coordinate frame to it and
我将从屏幕的表面取出z轴。
I am going to have the z-axis out of the face of the screen.
y轴在手机上垂直向上，x轴从左到右水平
The y-axis is vertically upwards on the phone and the x-axis is horizontal from left to
对。
right.
我打算称这个框架B代表车身框架或车身固定框架。
I am going to call this frame B and that stands for the body frame or the body-fixed frame.
这是航空航天和机器人技术中非常常见的符号。
This is a very common notation in aerospace and also in robotics.
现在我们要将一个加速度计与我们拥有的每个轴对齐
Now we are going to place one accelerometer aligned with each of the axes that we have
附在电话上。
attached to the phone.
因此，一个加速度计将处于XB方向，一个处于YB方向，一个处于XB方向
So, one accelerometer would be in XB direction and one in the YB direction and one in the
ZB方向。
ZB direction.
现代手机充满了惯性传感器。
Modern mobile phones, are packed full of inertial sensors.
它们包含三个加速度计，三个陀螺仪和三个磁力计。
They contained three accelerometers, three gyros and three magnetometers.
就像我们在本系列讲座中谈到的其他内容一样，我们将附上
Like everything else that we've talked about in this lecture series, we are going to attach
电话的坐标框架。
a coordinate frame to the phone.
您必须深入了解文档才能找到坐标框架
You have to look reasonably deeply into the documentation to find the coordinate frame
手机的惯例，但对于像这样的iPhone，惯例是x轴
conventions for the phone, but for an iPhone like this, the convention is the x-axis is
在右边，y轴是手机的顶部，而z轴是在手机的顶部
to the right and the y-axis is to the top of the phone and the z-axis is out of the
屏幕。
screen.
所以，我打算将一个标准坐标框架固定到手机上，这样我们才能理解它是什么
So, I am going to fix one of my standard coordinate frames to the phone, so we understand what's
什么。
what.
您可以为手机获取许多应用程序，报告加速度测量
There are many apps that you can get for your phone, that report the acceleration measurement
由手机内置的传感器记录。
recorded by the sensors built into the phone itself.
不幸的是，许多这些应用都带来了负面信号。
Unfortunately, many of these apps introduce a negative sign.
这意味着如果手机平放在桌子上，它会报告减去的值
That means that if the phone is sitting flat on the table, it reports a value of minus
1G在负z或向下与方向，但正如我们在上一节中讨论的，
1G in the negative z or down with the direction but as we discussed in the previous section,
平放在桌子上的设备的加速度应该是正向上的1G
acceleration of a device sitting flat on a table should be 1G in the positive upward
x方向。
x direction.
所以，在这里我们有铅锤，它在重力作用下垂下，所以它是
So, here we have the plumb bob, which is hanging down under the force of gravity, so it is
与重力加速度平行对齐，具有相同的重力加速度
aligned parallel to the gravitational acceleration with the same gravitational acceleration is
平行于z轴。
parallel to the z-axis.
如果我像这样旋转手机，那么现在，重力加速度是平行的
If I rotate the phone like this, so now, the gravitational acceleration is parallel to
y轴，现在我可以旋转手机，所以重力加速度是平行的
the y-axis and now I can rotate the phone, so the gravitational acceleration is parallel
到x轴。
to the x-axis.
现在让我们考虑一下确定电话方向的问题
Let us consider now the problem of determining the orientation of the phone with respect
世界坐标系。
to a world coordinate frame.
此处的世界坐标系显示为蓝色，其原点显示为z轴
The world coordinate frame is shown here in blue and its origin shows that the z-axis
向上并平行于重力矢量。
is upwards and parallel to the gravity vector.
框架B，车身框架牢固地连接到手机。
Frame B, the body frame is attached rigidly to the phone.
现在我可以根据世界坐标为手机的方向写一个表达式
Now I can write an expression for the orientation of the phone with respect to the world coordinate
框架和我将在连续的偏航，俯仰和滚转角度方面做到这一点
frame and I will do that in terms of yaw, pitch and roll angles which are successive
围绕z轴，y轴然后是x轴的旋转。
rotations about the z-axis, the y-axis and then the x-axis.
这是世界框架中的重力加速度，因为世界的z轴是
This is the gravitational acceleration in the world frame because the world z-axis is
平行于重力加速度矢量。
parallel to the gravitational acceleration vector.
我们在这里注意到G是正面的。
We note here that G is positive.
我们所说的世界框架中的加速度是G向上的方向。
We are talking about acceleration in the world frame is G in the upward direction.
相对于世界框架旋转这种重力加速度非常容易
It is very easy to rotate this gravitational acceleration with respect to the world frame
进入车身框架。
into the body frame.
这就是手机中的传感器实际测量的内容。
This is what the sensors in the phone actually measure.
他们正在测量相对于框架B的重力。值得注意的是
They are measuring gravity with respect to frame B. It is really important to note that
这假设手机没有加速。
this assumes that the phone is not accelerating.
身体上唯一的加速度是由于重力引起的。
The only acceleration on the body is that due to gravity.
现在，我可以扩展右侧，我可以用左侧替换
Now, I can expand out the right hand side and I can replace the left hand side with
通过手机中的传感器实际测量的重力。
the gravity actually measured by the sensors in the phone.
我有一个非常简单的矢量方程。
I have a very simple vector equation.
如果我在这个向量方程中取第一行。
If I take the first row in this vector equation.
我可以重新排列它以获得俯仰角θ的解决方案。
I can rearrange it to get a solution for the pitch angle theta.
如果我取向量方程中最后两行的商，我得到这个表达式
If I take the quotient of the last two rows in the vector equation, I get this expression
对于手机的滚动角度。
for the roll angle of the phone.
基于测量的加速度的两个非常简单的方程给出了滚转角和俯仰角
Two very simple equations based on the measured acceleration give me the roll and pitch angle
相对于世界坐标系的手机
of the phone with respect to the world coordinate frame.
然后你在这个等式中注意到没有出现偏航角。
Then you note in this equation that yaw angle does not appear.
一个简单的方法来思考为什么会这样，重力矢量有三个
A simple way to think about why this is the case, is that the gravity vector has got three
元素但其长度是固定的，因此我们只能通过两条信息来定义它。
elements but its length is fixed therefore we can define it by only two pieces of information.
重力矢量的第三个元素是多余的。
The third element of the gravity vector is redundant.
在这种情况下，我们需要的两条信息是侧倾角和俯仰角
In this case, the two pieces of information that we need are the roll angle and the pitch
角度。
angle.
我们不需要偏航角。
We do not need the yaw angle.
为了测量偏航角，我们需要使用不同的传感器，实际上是传感器
To measure the yaw angle, we need to use a different sensor and that sensor is actually
罗盘，这是我们下一节的主题。
a compass and that is the topic of our next section.
当我们使用三个加速度计时，一个重要的考虑因素是它仅测量两个
An important consideration when we use three accelerometers, is that it measures only two
自变量。
independent variables.
矢量的长度是固定的，因此，我们可以简单地描述该矢量
The length of the vector is fixed, so therefore, we can describe that vector just in terms
两个角度。
of two angles.
当手机配置如此时，我们可以非常清楚地看到。
We can see that very clearly when the phone is configured like this.
Z和X方向的零加速度。
Zero acceleration in the Z and the X directions.
加速度全部在Y方向。
The acceleration is all in the Y direction.
所以加速计的测量结果与这样的手机完全相同，
So the accelerometer measurements are exactly the same with the phone orientated like this,
或者像这样或者像这样。
or like this or like this.
它完全没有区别。
It makes absolutely no difference.
如今的加速度计成本非常低，但性能非常非常高。
Accelerometers today have very low cost but very, very high in performance.
部分原因是它们大量生产。
Part of the reason for this is that they are manufactured in enormous quantities.
它们用于触发汽车安全气囊。
They're use to trigger airbags in cars.
它们被用在数码相机中，以确定相机是横向还是纵向
They're used in digital cameras to work out whether the camera is in landscape or portrait
模式。
mode.
它们在手机中用于各种不同的应用程序，并且它们正在使用
They're used in your phone for all sorts of different applications and they're use the
从像这样的低成本玩具稳定车辆的无人区域到更多
stabilization of unmanned area of vehicles from low cost toys like this to much more
复杂的系统。
sophisticated systems.